and us in the car in colossal Amida
today I'm going to talk about the top
five programming myths that stop people
from learning how to program and that
make junior developers feel like they
are not good enough I used to believe
all these myths before and it really
slowed my progress
the first one is everybody can learn to
program this one it's a lie this one's a
lie that many companies tell you because
they want to sell you courses and books
and boot camps and videos and it's not
true people keep saying that everybody
can program because programming is easy
and fun and that anybody can do it well
it's not true not everybody can do that
it's not going to be enjoyable for
everybody and it's not going to be a
career path for everybody as a teacher I
can only tell you that there are some
people that are just not good or they're
just not made for programming just like
I am not made to dance ballet some
people are just different in that's okay
saying that everybody can be a
programmer is like saying that anybody
can be a painter now we can all take
paint and put it on the canvas but that
doesn't mean that we are going to be
good at me mixing colors or add
proportions or our shadows and most of
us are not going to enjoy painting I
hate painting you need to enjoy
logical thinking and problem-solving and
also you need to be okay with the fact
that most of the time spent programming
is frustrating is lonely not socializing
in front of a computer feeling like you
are an idiot
because your code doesn't work at 3:00
a.m. in the morning
this is why if you ask programmers if
they really enjoy programming per se
they will say no programming per se it's
very very frustrating boring unknowing
whatever you want to call it but what
you will see is that programmers enjoy
programming because of the result
because of what happens when you finish
what happens when you push through that
frustration angel code is finally there
programming is not for everyone
programming can be painful can be
frustrating everybody should know this
but also it's worth it number two
programming is memorization beginners
approach programming the same way that
they approach studying for an exam in
college well it's all about remembering
but not understanding this is especially
true in Korea where everything is
focused on the result on the exam rather
than on the process programming is the
opposite first you need to understand
the concepts and then you get to
remember them it is not about
memorization whatsoever to make a great
piece of software you do not need to
remember all the keywords on the
programming language or whatever you're
using you need to logically understand
the problem that you need to solve and
what tools you have available so then
you can make use of the tools to fix it
most programmers do not remember
anything most programmers Google at all
times
senior programmers are not seniors
because they remember everything I never
used Google senior programmers code less
and make more money than juniors because
they just have a better view and
understanding of all the systems and all
the landscapes of the software
development world if you want to be a
good programmer don't try to memorize
try to gain understanding third number
three is you gotta be a genius to be a
programmer this one is a big one because
of what we see on the movies most of the
time is some like kind of wizard kid
that is on the screen typing really fast
never making any mistakes and just hack
into the White House in the United
States now this is not what a good
programmer is or what a good hacker even
is this myth is the one that hits
hardest for junior programmers that feel
like they are not good enough they don't
feel ready to ask for a job so they keep
studying and studying and studying and
studying and this especially happens in
Korea where everyone wants to be at the
top and being at the middle is not good
enough and actually you don't need to be
a genius to program there are just ok
programmers they are the average they
are good enough decent good enough
ok programmer is what most of us are you
don't have to be a genius programmer to
be able to get a job to start your own
company you can just be good enough and
that is ok in the programming word
number four is programmers are talented
if you know how to program is because
you have a talent that God gave you or
something now I'm a firm believer that
disciplined beat talent sure maybe there
are some people that are better at
computers there are some people that
maybe will understand something like
distributed cloud database systems
faster if I explain to them but
programming is not a game of talent
programming is a game of persistence
programming is basically saying okay I'm
not gonna go to sleep
until I fix this function I am going to
find this bug I'm not gonna get angry
and I'm going to read and do everything
again what it takes to be a programmer
is not talent what takes to be a
programmer is not given up programming
is a constant fight with the machine
that's how you win you win by not giving
up you don't win with talent if you have
focus if you are disciplined
if you are patient you are going to be a
better programmer that's somebody else
that has a talent but cannot focus
number five you need to be good at math
the reason why I put this one here is
because many people make it look like
math and being good at math is a
requirement to learn to program and that
is not true
now it's not a requirement but it helps
if you don't like math can you still
learn to program yes what can you do if
you suck at math you can do websites
front-ends backends databases full stack
you can do iOS apps android apps even
some many maybe some video games as well
but you're going to have a ceiling over
your head you're going to have some
limits for example you won't be able to
do something like a physics engine or
create machine learning models or work
with something like self-driving cars or
maybe even some stock-exchange
automation now if you want to do these
things you are going to need math if you
want to do the sort of things that Tony
Stark would do you need math I suck at
math and I'm happy that I'm never going
to build a self-driving car I don't care
about building a self-driving car so I'm
happy don't all right that was the top
five myths programming is not for
everyone
programming is not memorization not only
geniuses can program programming is not
a talent game and if you suck at math
you can still be a programmer thank you
so much for watching this video thank
you so much for listening to me for
leaving comments for limited like let me
know what you think is the myth number
six on the comments we're so close to
100k thank you so much for your support
you know i7 Hale very very very much and
as always come Sameera there